the judge at the county of student
levels and resources serves as National
president of the Italian Sons and
Daughters of America and the committee
on the local and National
Italian organisms
[Applause]
thank you very much
thank you again by respectfully saying
that we have six very very special
individuals that are going to be
recognize this evening and if the most
fuel to win the world that seem to feel
the need to continue to socialize while
this program that's going on I would ask
that you showed up the courtesy of
respect that each of them intelligence
[Applause]
this exceptional event is so very
important because it gives us all the
opportunity to celebrate our differences
to learn more from each other about our
respective cultures and heritages and in
the process to develop a mutual respect
for The Unique contributions each and
every one of our communities have made
it to our country's great elective
culture
requirements with their opportunity
the Italian American Community is
honored to present what I can host the
program you described as a Renaissance
woman for induction into the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame
Joyce Mariani has chosen to devote her
life to the celebration of the classical
artists as a young woman after studying
in Italy
to pursued a successful career synopsis
having performed with the national
orchestral of Italy throughout Italy
Europe and Independence Severance Hall
upon her return to Cleveland Joyce
initiated many exceptional cultural
programs that have enriched the lives of
so many greater Communications
beginning in 2006
found it and continues to serve as an
executive director of the Cleveland
Italian Film Festival
when each September showcases after
winning Italian tourists and in multiple
theaters throughout our community
she also founded Eva La Cultura Italiana
a unique cultural program which has
created a special performance titled
approached in the Italian Garden
each July is President program presents
performances by the Cleveland Opera and
the Cleveland ballets and the Italian
cultural cabinet to an audience of over
3 000 convention free of charge
speaking of the Italian culture
speaking of the Italian cultural guard
because also serves as an executive
director of the Italian cultural
character Federation and has
successfully raised and managed a 1.5
million dollar Renaissance
restoration from the garden
not limited to the celebration of the
creative arts Joyce is also undertaken
an event to promote Italian culinary
numbers
which she has afternoon a private Soul
the Italian term for an elephant dinner
this event focuses on presenting the
specialized Cuisine of the different
regions of Italy as prepared by The
Local Economic Italian chefs
as if everything I've mentioned were not
sufficient to demand all of the time
Joyce also runs official time to lecture
and write about the history of the
Renaissance Gardens as well as that of
Cleveland's Italian cultural health
appreciates and promotes the cultural
apps a woman who was devoted her life to
enriching the lives of all of those who
live in our community
an Italian-American Community is proud
to present Joyce Miami as an inductee
into the Cleveland International Hall of
Fame
it was truly unexpected
congratulations to my fellow inductees
I'd also like to express my gratitude to
the board of the Italian culture Garden
for the guidance
to kill the manteel for all your current
help
and all the Italian Garden volunteers
who devotedly gave up their time to
maintain the beautiful plants and large
fountains
[Music]
I don't know if you know the show but I
if you remember my very first city
Landmark presentation in 2007
Towing the large land post project to
the Italian Garden you came running out
of the room to shake my hand and give me
encouragement how great she thought it
was that an ordinary citizen was raising
the funds this meant a lot to me just
starting out so thank you
our attitude to death again Hanson who
for many years had accepted the
International Community together
with your efforts sharing everyone's
activities
I always keep in mind that no man is an
island
none of us who have achieving anything
did it alone in a vacuum
one may have Vision but we all need the
help of others at some point to gently
lift our dreams
coming to the U.S after living in
Infinity
my desire was to create
community-wide cultural events and
perpetually our Italian culture
[Music]
beyond our well-known Cuisine campus
I wondered why the acclaimed Oscar
winning Italian forms the world over
flew over Cleveland to other cities
or San Francisco
and noted that Cleveland is one of the
major cities in the country without an
independent Italian Film Festival
[Music]
Festival was born and has sold out each
year since its beginning except during
the pandemic
we often choose a road to travel in life
and sometimes
where we think we will
because after that first year of the
film festival
Gino collage introduced me to the
Italian cultural Garden
I was so surprised to see a
magnificently designed Renaissance
Garden much like the Renaissance Gardens
near my home in the world
and in Cleveland of all places with
massive families one of which is modeled
after the village she found you
[Music]
so began the 1.5 million dollar
restoration of the Italian culture
Garden
I learned a tremendous sacrifice and
struggles a trio of immigrant founders
of the Italian Garden immigrants who
came here with nothing
and one rose to become the head of city
council one headed important artist from
Italy that decorated the Ohio Theater in
200 theaters across the country and
another became Millennium architects
I remember the determination to build
such a majestic public space during the
Depression
along with the hard work
believed that this public space
should reflect the Majesty of thousands
of years of cultural history
and we can think of just the
contributions from the Renaissance alone
all the Arts music and all of the
Sciences
the real meaning of this public space
was lost three to three years
it wasn't just a flower girl
but a public cultural Monument to Italy
honoring cultural grades in the Arts and
Sciences and arts and letters
I learned the majority of my community
and the general public were mostly
unaware of this Grand space
historic restoration is very expensive
so I decided having never raised money
before to focus my passion on the idea
itself
to convey to donors to Joy and Beauty
people would experience with the
finished project
Diana Freeland is found the same
the greatest thing in life is passion
without it what have you got
for when you have a dream
your passion convinces others
to tap into your dream
and then it becomes a reality
the illustrious history of the Italy and
its enormous impact on the world gave me
the determination to begin
while envisioning a outdoor unique
outdoor Museum I read hundreds of
cultural figures showing Italy's impact
in the world
[Music]
the Italian Garden is the most
consistently flavor intensive with
hundreds of plants alone that need
pruning every year
[Music]
it was the first Garden to go green 16
years ago and has a large part stage of
heat along with two very large
Renaissance fountains on the upper and
lower levels
it was the first Garden all he could
have comprehensive lighting with 19
historic land posts on both levels
my cultural heritage
Heritage inborn feelings for beauty
creativity and a passion for living that
manifested itself to its brilliant
accomplishments
its gifts to the Western Civilization
of art architecture literature science
law medicine civil planning engineering
and music and all of the Arts began with
the Romans and reached a high point at
the beginning of the 14th century
Renaissance
the great 16th century architect who the
111th Congress recently Paul the father
of American architecture
whose influence culminated in the U.S
Capitol building and the White House
where would the art of poetry leader
without the Divine Comedy of Dante
olivieri whose statue raises the Italian
Garden
and an influence generation of writers
artists down through the centuries and
the wooden Museum
who invented a way to put the first
written musical notes on paper
that people could read and spot the
creation of the first operation
the great Italian Renaissance could be
produced in the Arts and Sciences
Michelangelo to Galileo to the great
Leonardo da Vinci whose atomical studies
of the human body was so perfect that
they were used until the 19th century
our paintings would appear without
Dimension were not for Leon Batista
Alberti the initiator of the Renaissance
art principle of perspective
from the inventors of the piano the
violin and the cello it's hard to
imagine a world without the influence of
Italy in the Western Union
it's not only all of our cultural
Customs that nurture us but a detailed
message of our societal culinary
and cultural habits combined
aside from our unique individualities
we also see I understand we are all one
we love the same things in life love our
family friends Customs while stepping
outside of ourselves to live in harmony
since the majority of us in this room
can identify with an existing cultural
Garden
to my fellow cultural Gardens and the
numerous new Gardens coming in before
without the work of hundreds of
volunteers and their communities there
would not be a private cultural Gardens
for it is a day we have kept this large
swath of over 70 Acres restored
rehabilitated
and running
is how to sacrifice and constant hard
work there would be no Cost Plus for
beautiful statues
we could not have one world day all
through the years without many months of
hard work and planning by individual
Gardens presenting concerts
offering as an inclusive and nationality
of arts and crafts
without all these dedicated Garden
volunteers there would be no beautiful
landscapes interesting with color in the
spring of the summer lastly
[Music]
without these devoted volunteers and
garden heads plant execute and raise the
money needed by themselves what is known
as the cultural Gardens would once again
mirror the period when the gardens came
to a halt
during the turbulent 1960s
it should be healed without these
volunteers the cultural Gardens would
wither and descend into disrepair which
they did and the media frequently
appointed out
my fellow Garden heads often hear from
the general public a misconception that
the gardens are funded either by the
Cleveland cultural Garden Federation or
the city of Cleveland for their project
Restorations and maintenance
in reality is that the cultural Gardens
have been for now
for over 100 years and an unbroken chain
for Gardens and our ethnic community
volunteers have sustained themselves by
finding their own funding their
maintenance Restorations cultural
figures and creationism and Gardens
certain projects that meet criteria are
aided in part by the benevolence of the
Holy Trust
support your cultural Gardens for
represents the glory of your cultural
heritage
and in at the end of this month take it
right by the Italian culture Garden
because we have 1 300 tulips in coming
up to being bloom in the past the
cultural Gardens chose their leadership
from within their ranks but today we're
happening a new leadership of the
Federation Larry Ashton and Dr wild
Curry
they are working in tandem in the
gardens to forge new products
in the 1930s and 1940s Opera concerts
were given in the Italian culture Garden
because its founding mission statement
was that it was not only a physical
presence but it was a symbol of a
contribution of Italian culture to
American democracy
bringing back the annual Opera concerts
in 2008 after a 62-year absence was
important to give the cultural arts of
Italy to the public
namely because Opera and ballet both
originated in Italy
the concert became very popular with
thousands attending each year
today the operating Italian Garden now
in its 16th year draws people from all
over Northern Ohio and is funded mainly
by the Italian Sons and Daughters of
America and Cuyahoga arts and culture
two prestigious companies the Cleveland
ballet and the demon copper performed
every year
it's very interesting that the
popularity of this concert in the
beginning helped reintroduce the
cultural garments that were in Slumber
and under the radar of the public at
that time
long gone are the days in 2007 and for
numerous years afterwards when we heard
from the Commerce Republic we didn't
know these beautiful gardens right here
early this year
much needed new doors open when Cuyahoga
County looked into ways to help the
African-American Garden dedicated in
to complete complete their Garden after
but there is another cultural Garden
that's not completed that many aren't
aware of
and that's the Italian cultural record
dedicated in 1930.
after 93 years the Italian Garden hopes
to explore the same Avenues to receive
assistance to complete a domed Pantheon
structure originally planned but never
completed our own 200 cultural figures
beginning with the ancient Romans
accomplishments of the Renaissance
to modern day with the central statue of
Galileo who are open Einstein called the
father of American Science
thank you to councilman Kevin Caldwell
and the city of Cleveland we have a
wonderful progress to the Italian Garden
since 2007 and who understand the
importance of a partnership between
Civic volunteers and the city thank you